(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-16T22:20:35.492274",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
Hey DJ カマせ yeah×3
Hey DJ, drop the beat, yeah!
気分上々↑↑の
High spirits going up, up, up!
針落とせ 音鳴らせ
Drop the needle, sound the alarm!
パーリナイ 飲もうライライライ
It's a party night, let's drink, right, right, right!
みんなで踊れ！ hip-pop ピーポー
Everybody, dance! Hip-hop, people!
かけてよ ミラクルNumber
Spin that miracle number for us!
気分上々↑↑
High spirits going up, up, up!
こんな時代に分かち合う music
Sharing music to match these times,
探したくて回す地球儀
I want to spin the globe to find it.
グラつく不安定生活
Life is shaky and unstable,
それだからバランス重視
That's why balance is key.
良いことばかりじゃないから「頑張れる！」
It's not all good, but we can do our best!
最悪な日にキック
Kick the worst days away,
再起動のボタン クリック！
And click the reboot button!
DJ かけて！！ 今 trip
DJ, play it! Take a trip now!
シャレてるビートに乗って 感じる身体揺らそうよ
Ride the stylish beat and let loose your body!
Hey DJ カマせ yeah×3
Hey DJ, drop the beat, yeah!
気分上々↑↑の
High spirits going up, up, up!
針落とせ 音鳴らせ
Drop the needle, sound the alarm!
パーリナイ 飲もうライライライ
It's a party night, let's drink, right, right, right!
みんなで踊れ！ hip-pop ピーポー
Everybody, dance! Hip-hop, people!
かけてよ ミラクルNumber
Spin that miracle number for us!
hip hop, r&b, pops, techno, house, rock, hip-hop!!
オリジナル探す キーポイント
Finding our own style, key point!
それぞれの色重ね合わせ レインボー
Layering our colors into a rainbow!
君に聞かせたいが為苦しめあげくの果て
To let you hear it, after all the suffering...
十字固め
Hold the cross shape,
今を楽しみたいんだね
I want to enjoy the present!
Let's hip-pop!! Here we, here we go!!
はしゃぐフロアの上頭中ゆさゆさぶる
Playing on the floor, shaking your brain
Hey DJ シャシャれ yeah, yeah, yeah 気分上々↑↑の
Hey DJ, spin it, yeah, yeah, yeah, feeling great,
針落とせ 音鳴らせ パーリナイ
Drop the needle, make some noise, party night,
飲もう ライライライ みんなで踊れ!
Let's drink, right, right, right, everybody dance!
Hip-pop ピーポ 朝までミラクルNumber
Hip-pop people, miracle number all night long
ミラーボールスモークのにおい
Mirrorball, the smell of smoke,
溶けるようなハーモニー
A harmony that'll make you melt,
身にまとって踊り明かすがむしゃらなままで
Wrap it around you and dance the night away recklessly
Hey DJ カマセ yeah, yeah, yeah 気分上々↑↑の
Hey DJ, spin it, yeah, yeah, yeah, feeling great,
針落とせ 音鳴らせ パーリナイ
Drop the needle, make some noise, party night,
飲もう ライライライ みんなで踊れ!
Let's drink, right, right, right, everybody dance!
Hip-pop ピーポ かけてよ ミラクルNumber
Hip-pop people, play that miracle number
Hey DJ シャシャれ yeah, yeah, yeah 気分上々↑↑の
Hey DJ, spin it, yeah, yeah, yeah, feeling great,
波に乗って弾け飛べ ファンキーナイ
Drop the needle, make some noise, party night,
飲もう ライライライ みんなで踊れ!
Let's drink, right, right, right, everybody dance!
Hip-pop ピーポ 朝までミラクルNumber
Hip-pop people, miracle number all night long
Hey DJ カマセ yeah, yeah, yeah
Hey DJ, spin it, yeah, yeah, yeah,
飲もう ライライライ
Let's drink, right, right, right,
カマセ yeah, yeah, yeah
Spin it, yeah, yeah, yeah,
飲もう ライライライ
Let's drink, right, right, right,
カマセ yeah, yeah, yeah
Spin it, yeah, yeah, yeah,
飲もう ライライライ
Let's drink, right, right, right,
カマセ yeah, yeah, yeah
Spin it, yeah, yeah, yeah,
飲もう ライライライ
Let's drink, right, right, right,
Hey DJ カマセ yeah, yeah, yeah!
Hey DJ, spin it, yeah, yeah, yeah!
はい、というわけで! イエーイ!
All right, and with that! Yay!
あの、みんな今日なんで集まってんのか知ってる?
Does everyone know why we're gathered here today?
知らない! わかんない!
No clue!
わかんないけえ!
You don't know?
気分上々だった! あ、よっしゃ!
I'm in a great mood! Yay!
今日ね、あのね、うちの誕生日なんだ!
Well, today is my birthday!
おめでとう! おめでとう! おめでとう!
Happy birthday! Congratulations!
ありがとう! ありがとう! かわいい!
Thank you! Thank you! Aw, how sweet!
みんな、あの、うちが誕生日ケーキを食べるために、
So, you see, in order to eat birthday cake...
うーん、なんか、あの、まあ、ただじゃ食べれないよみたいな感じなんだよね、毎年。
Like, you can't just eat it for free, right?
そうなんだね。そうそう。
Ah, I see.
でね、あのね、今日は、足元をご覧ください!
So, please take a look at your feet!
ええー! すごろく!
Whoa, Sugoroku?!
すごろくが始まります!
We're playing Sugoroku!
すごろく! はい! はい!
Yay! Yes!
え、こちらのね、すごろくで、
So, with this Sugoroku,
1位をうちが取れたら、ケーキが食べれるという事で、ええー!
Whoever gets 1st place gets to eat the cake!
ええー! なにこれ! なにこれ!
Yay! What is this?!
で、このように、ま、このメンバーの中で、
And so, out of this group of members,
1位になった人がケーキを食べれるというルールなので、うち取ります! はい! うち取ります!
Whoever wins 1st place gets to eat the cake—wait.
うち、うちが誕生日なんだけどね。
I mean, it's my birthday, but...
そう。
Right.
じゃ、食べ、とりま、とりま、うちも食べたいんだけど、
I want to eat it, but...
ま、でもなんか、ただじゃ食べるのあれだから、代償取られなきゃいけないっていう、そういうルールがありまして。
Well, but since it's not free to eat, you gotta pay the price, you know?
じゃあ、とりあえずすごろくやってみようー!
So, let's play Sugoroku!
誕生日、夏の地獄すごろく!
The Birthday Hell Sugoroku!
始まる、始まる! すごろく始まる、こちらね。
It's starting! The Sugoroku is starting!
なんか急に始まるすごろくだな。
Wait, why is this starting so suddenly?
あの、あれですか、なん、なん期生汁みたいな感じのやつ?
Like, what is this? Some kind of initiation ritual?
あ、じゃ、一番最初な、今日はバラバラだし。次すごろく!
Oh, wait, let's roll the dice!
はい、じゃ、ゴロゴロって感じか。ちょっと、振っちゃってよ。振っちゃって。振っちゃって。
Let's roll it! Roll it! Roll it!
なんな!
Nan-na!
お、2、2!
Two! Two!
1、お? 2、ないくえ!
One! Two! No way!
ははは、あれだけね。
Wait, that was just...
宝鐘マリン!
Houshou Marine?!
やばい!
Seriously?!
どういうこと?!
What does that mean?!
す、す、す、す、す、ちょ、ストップストップ。
Wait, wait, wait, hold on!
すいません。あの、宝鐘マリンでーす。
Sorry everyone, I'm Houshou Marine!
お、似合ってる?
What are you doing?!
ずっと船長嫌なんです。
I really don't want to be captain.
普通のすごろくじゃないじゃん！
This isn't a normal board game!
なんなんですか？
What is this?
あー！船長！やばい！やばい！
Ah! Captain! Oh no, oh no!
めっちゃ進んだ！早く投げてくだしゃい！
You moved so far! Hurry up and roll!
似てるんだよ、早く投げてくだしゃい。
It looks like it, hurry up and roll.
どーあちゃんが？どーあちゃんが？
Doa-chan? Doa-chan?
きますかね？あ、来ました、来ましたよ。
Will she come? Ah, she's here, she's here.
やばい。
Oh no.
あほーい！宝鐘マリンです！
Ahoi! It's Houshou Marine!
大丈夫なこれ？どうやってやるんですか？
Is this okay? How do you do it?
あ、逆だった。逆です。
Ah, it was backwards. It's backwards.
あほーい！宝鐘マリンです！どんなガビガビなんですか？
Ahoi! It's Houshou Marine! Why is the audio so crusty?
はい、じゃあ、うちゅふりまーすね！うちゃあんなんちゅが、ふれです！
Okay, then I'll roll! Baby talk is the rule!
３です！
It's a 3!
わーい！回避すんだです！...おだにそん？進んじゃった。
Yay! Evading! ...Odani-son? You moved ahead.
船長じゃなくて、普通のおばあやん。
You're not the captain, you're just a normal old lady.
いや、そんなおばあさんじゃない！そんなおばあさんって言わないでくだしゃい！
Hey, I'm not that kind of old lady! Don't call me that!
え？え？あかちゃんじゃん？
Huh? Huh? Aren't you a baby?
次のターンまで、ミオしゃ小足で移動！えー！こんなので？
Until the next turn, move with Mio-sha's tippy-toes! Eh! Like this?
それめっちゃおもろいじゃん！次のターンまで結構長いな。
That's so funny! Until the next turn is pretty long.
いや、本家だから、まあ、まあ、まあ、まあまあ。
Well, it's the original, so, well, well, well.
次のターンいきます！
Going to the next turn!
２ターンって、ここ２ターンじゃない？ていうか、違います、あの、２回サイコロ振るやつです。
Two turns, isn't this two turns? Wait, no, um, it's rolling the dice twice.
何ですか？
What is it?
１です！
It's a 1!
１はなんですか？
What is 1?
あかちゃんや！
It's a baby!
うーちゃん！あらあら、あかちゃんでちゅねー！
U-chan! Oh my, it's a baby!
あかちゃんでちゅねー。
It's a baby.
あかちゃん！ほんとにすごい、うちゃいでちゅねー！
Baby! Really amazing, it's so noisy!
なんだかかわいいでちゅねー。
Somehow it's cute.
いやー、うるさいでちゅねー。
Man, it's so noisy.
めっちゃうるさいでちゅ！んぎゅんぎゅ！
It's super noisy! Ngungyu ngungyu!
よちよち、よしよし、でちゅおか？
Pat pat, there there, is that so?
じゃあ、次、船長ね。
Now next, Captain.
１です！
It's a 1!
あかちゃん言葉はもう１人生まれた！
Another person born speaking baby talk!
あかちゃんになっちゃいました！あーんぎゃー！
You became a baby! Aaangya!
のりのりだ！あかちゃんになれないか。
They're into it! Can't you become a baby?
あぶぶぶぶ……あかちゃんだ！あーすごーい！おしゃぶりしてる！
Abubububu... A baby! Ah amazing! Using a pacifier!
船長、ねえ、でちゅー！え、それ、船長じゃないよ、それ！
Captain, hey, dechu! Eh, that's not the Captain, that!
やばい！あかちゃんになっちゃったでちゅ！
Oh no! You became a baby dechu!
あ、３です。
Ah, it's 3.
１、２、３。なんだこれ？しりもじ！
1, 2, 3. What is this? Butt letters!
しりもじ！お題の単語を尻文字で伝えろ！他のメンバーが当てられたら２マス進む。
Butt letters! Convey the given word using butt letters! If other members guess it, advance 2 squares.
はい、じゃあ、みんなはこっちだよ。了解です。
Okay, everyone is over here. Understood.
じゃあ、船長のお尻見ててください。いきますよ。
Okay, watch the Captain's butt. Here we go.
あ、わかったでちゅ！りんご！
Ah, I figured it out dechu! Apple!
わかんない！答えは？
I don't know! What's the answer?
これってでも、答えたら？
Even so, if we answer?
いや、答えてほしいんです。
No, I want you to answer.
あかちゃん、でちゅか？ベイビー？
Baby, dechu ka? Baby?
違う違う違う！いってくださいよ！いってくださいよ！
No no no! Say it! Say it!
船長、おとに、答えてください、トワ様。早く。
Captain, oto-ni, please answer, Towa-sama. Hurry.
りんご。
Apple.
正解！やったー！
Correct! Yay!
やったー！ありがとうございます！すごい！やばいです！
Yay! Thank you very much! Amazing! This is crazy!
すっごい、すっごい！なんか、赤ちゃんみたいなってきたぞ。
So amazing, so amazing! Somehow you've become like a baby.
船長のお尻をわかっていただいたトワ様なので。
Since Towa-sama understood the Captain's butt.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
えでも、２ターンだから、まだ続くんだね。
Eh, but it's two turns, so it's still going.
しりもじが、えっと、クリアできたということは、何マス進めるんだっけ？あ、なんかありましたっけ？
Since butt-letters was cleared, how many squares do we advance again? Ah, was there something?
２マス進める！おー！
Advance 2 squares! Oh!
じゃあ、次、船長ね。
Okay, next, Captain.
次の船長。
Next Captain.
船長、いきますです！
Captain, here we go!
どうぞ。
Go ahead.
なんてたってんだ！
What did you roll!
２マスです！おー！
2 squares! Oh!
ちょっぴりキャラ、おけけった！
Slightly in character, okeketta!
船長、そんな歩き方すんの？
Captain, is that how you walk?
ここはなんだ？ここはなんだ？
What is this? What is this?
ひとつ先の人に愛の告白！
Love confession to the person one square ahead!
船長の、船長の、告白するんですか？
The Captain's, the Captain's confession?
そういうことです！じゃあ、白上船長にね。
That's what it means! So, to Shirakami Captain.
ひとつ先の人に愛の告白、YESをもらえたら１マス進みますんでね。
Love confession to the person one square ahead, if you get a YES you advance 1 square.
真剣にやれよ！
Do it seriously!
それできょとたもってなです。
Do it so you can keep your composure.
真剣にやれよ！うわー！ドキドキする！
Do it seriously! Woah! My heart is pounding!
じゃあ、船長近づきます。
Okay, Captain is approaching.
ドン！おいふぶき、俺のものにならないか？
Bam! Hey Fubuki, won't you become mine?
おっ、これは！
Oh, this is!
ドン！
Bam!
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
告白成功じゃないですよね！
Wait, that's not a confession success!
そうですね！
That's right!
ちょっとお礼を言いまして、お礼を。
So we felt like doing that.
お礼をね！
The feeling, right?
これはまだ進めるんですか？
Can we still move forward?
1個進むということで、1個1個。
You move forward by one, so one by one.
はい。
Yes.
あ、ここですよ、ここ。
So it's here, right here.
あ、ここで「尻文字」回避ね、じゃあ。
Ah, so here is "Butt Writing".
ちょっと進もうとして止まって…
I was trying to move, but...
チュウ！ちゅうい！
Towa-chuu!
ちゅうい！チュウ！
mioちゃんがどこまで行けるか、がんばれー！
Let's see how far you can go, Mio-chama!
はい、じゃ行きましょう。お、ごろごろごろ！
Alright, let's go. Oh, roll, roll, roll!
なんですか？ごろごろごろ！
What is it? Roll, roll, roll!
2ですね、2。
It's two, right? Two.
あ、小走り小走り小走り！
Ah, small steps, small steps, small steps!
ここは、尻文字です！
So, it's butt writing!
尻文字！尻文字！
Butt writing! Butt writing!
尻文字ポジションに行きたいと思います。
I want to get to the butt writing position.
尻文字！
Butt writing!
がんばります！
We'll do our best.
みおしゃがんばれです！
Mio-chama, do your best!
いきますよ！
Let's go!
全然わからないですね！全然わからない！
I have no idea at all!
一文字の文字じゃない！
It's a two-character word!
すごい難しい。
It's super difficult.
どう？
How?
ちょっとわからない。
I don't really get it.
わかんない、わかんないだな。
I don't get it, I don't get it.
ちょっと船長もこれには…
Even the captain...
そうですね、ちょっと船長を悩ませますね。
It's making the captain's head hurt.
わかんなかった！
I didn't get it.
でもう1回、もう1回、がんばります！
Do it again, do it again!
はい、お願いします！
Please, Mio!
船長、わかりました！
Captain, I got it!
ずばり、プリンです！
It's "pudding"!
ぴんぽんぴんぽん！ぴんぽん！
Pudding!
すごい！すごいですね、船長！
Amazing, amazing!
ずばりプリンです！
Spot on, it's pudding!
やったー！
Yay!
これは…
And for this...
成功すると、2マス進めます！
If you succeed, you move two squares!
やった！
Yay!
じゃあ、船長と同じとこですね。ここですね。
So, captain, you're at the same place.
あ、ここですね。
You're right here.
早くこの船長の呪縛から…
Hurry up and break the captain's curse!
とかれてほしい！
Release it!
動かない！進進進まない！
It's not moving!
ちょっと2マスだった！
It's only two squares!
いちごベビー！はい！
It's "Ichigo Baby"!
いちごベビー！
"Ichigo Baby"!
お、に！に！に！
Two! Two!
に！に！はい！はい！
じゃあ、あかちゃんは呪縛は解けるのかな？
Wait, can Ichigo-chan break the curse?
え？あ、うち、小足で移動してなかった。
Eh? Ah, we didn't move with small steps!
小足で移動…どういうことこれ？
You didn't move with small steps? What's this?
次のターンまで“ミオしゃ小足で移動”。
Next turn is small step movement.
オッケーです！
Okay!
あ、小走りないですね。小走りないから。
Oh, no small steps?
ああ、よかった。小走りなくて。
Ah, I'm glad.
あかちゃんから解かれたから。
Because Akachan got caught by it.
みおしゃ、みおしゃ、小足で取ってほしいですよ！
Mio-sha, Mio-sha, take it with small steps, please!
小足！小足！小足！あの本家の小足が見たい！
Small steps! Small steps! Small steps! The real small steps!
小足、小足、小足！
Small steps, small steps, small steps!
本物だきっと！
It must be the real deal!
小足で！
With small steps!
ありがとうございます！けけきゃん！
Thank you! Ke-ke-kyan!
何なんですかね？お！プリン！
Let's see what it is!
プリンです！
It's pudding!
またこっち来るの？
You're coming here again?
ノリノリだったけどさ。
I was having fun, but...
あなたあかちゃんでしょ！
You're Akachan?
ばかにしてる！
You're making fun of me!
小足！
Small steps!
ばかにされてるから！
You're being made fun of!
準備完了よ！
Get ready!
全然！全然違います！
Totally different!
あかちゃんの呪縛から解かれたということで。
It's because you were caught by Akachan's curse.
解かれたやつ！
The person who was cursed!
次はね、ふぶきですよ！
Next is...
あ、じゃあ船長の呪縛が解けた！
Ah, so the captain's curse has been lifted!
やったー！
Yay!
さらばマリン！よし！
Tora Marine! Yay!
なんだ！
Nanda!
に！に！いち！ろく！
Two, one, six!
ろく！ろくあるよね、本当に。
Six! There's a six, right?
全員とじゃんけん！
Everyone rock-paper-scissors!
全員と一人ずつじゃんけん勝負！負けたら1マス戻る。
Rock-paper-scissors with everyone individually! If you lose, you go back one square.
え？え？え？え？
What? What? What? What?
てことは？
That means...
全員とじゃんけん？
Rock-paper-scissors with everyone?
全員とじゃんけんして？
最大4マス戻る。
Go back up to four squares.
4マス戻る！
Go back four squares!
じゃあちょっとじゃあ、みおからいくか。
Then, let's start with Mio.
じゃ行きましょうか？
Shall we go?
最初はグー、じゃんけんぽん！
Rock, paper, scissors, ho!
あいこでしょ！あいこでしょ！
Aiko de sho! Aiko de sho!
まず1マス戻る。
Go back one square!
いきますよ！最初で！
First! We'll go first!
最初はグー、じゃんけんぽん！
Rock, paper, scissors, ho!
あいこでしょ！あいこでしょ！あいこでしょ！あいこでしょ！
Aiko de sho! Aiko de sho! Aiko de sho! Aiko de sho!
よしよし！
Yoisho!
よし！
Nice!
え、次の人！最初で、じゃんけんぽん！
Next is the next person! Rock, paper, scissors, ho!
1マス戻る！
Go back one square!
最初で、じゃんけんぽん！
Rock, paper, scissors, ho!
2マス戻る！
Go back two squares!
ってこと戻って来るだけ？
So you just go back?
まあまあまあ、いいですよ、船長。
Well, that's fine, right, captain?
安全分ね。
At least you're safe.
はい、じゃあ次ね。
Alright, then next!
じゃあ、船長の呪縛が解けた！
Ah, so the captain's curse has melted!
よっしゃ！
Yossha!
呪縛！
Cursed!
最初から別珍だったけど。
You were cursed from the start, weren't you?
確かにね。
That's true.
これは1？1です！
This is one? It's one!
1？
One?
また1だ！
Another one!
あ、すごい扇子付いてる！
Oh, you get a fan!
あ、すごいじゃん。
Oh, it's amazing!
お嬢様ですわ！お！
It's like a princess!
お！
Oh!
みなのしゅう、がんばりなさい！
Minano-shu, do your best!
なんかシュート目ありますね。
Wait, is there a shooting check?
5とかがありますけども
There are 5s and 6s, but...
じゃあちょっとうち振って
Then roll it for me.
はいどうぞ
Sure, go ahead.
ミオちゃんずっと扇子振るんだ
Mio-chan's been waving her fan the whole time.
なんですか？
What is it?
でかい、でかい！
It's huge! It's huge!
やばい、5マス、6マスだって、消える
Oh no, 5 or 6 spaces, we'll disappear!
ここだ！
Right here!
ここだ！ここ！
Here! Right here!
ジェスチャーゲーム！
Gesture Game!
お題をジェスチャーで伝えろ！ 誰かに伝わったら2マス進む
Convey the prompt through gestures! If someone gets it, advance 2 spaces!
じゃあ尻文字ポイントに行きまして
Then let's head to the butt-writing checkpoint...
ジェスチャー？
Gesture?
ジェスチャーですって。お題が…
It says gesture. The prompt is...
あ、後ろにあるみたいだからみんな見ちゃだめだよ
Ah, it seems to be behind me, so everyone shouldn't look.
なるほどね！
I see!
わかりましたわ
I understand.
あ、はい！
Oh, right!
いいですか？
Are you ready?
いや、いきますよ
Yup, here we go.
おー、よーいスタート！
Ready, set, go!
さ、さ、さ、さ、さ、さ、さ……
Hmm...
言葉は出してるやん、言葉出してる
You're making sounds! You're making sounds!
なんデスのそれは！
What is that supposed to be?!
なんだろう、恐竜？ 亀？ 遠吠え！
What is it, a dinosaur? A turtle? Howling!
遠吠えですわ！
It's howling!
オオカミの遠吠えですわ！
It's a wolf's howling!
オオカミ！ すげー！
Wolf! Amazing!
じゃあお嬢様なのですわ
Well then, as an ojou-sama...
これって2マス進むってこと？
Does that mean advancing 2 spaces?
そうです。なんでって？
That's right. Why?
すごい進むやん。すごい進むやん
You advance so much. You advance so much!
うちはいひとりぼっちになっちゃうかも知れんね
Wait, I might end up all alone.
ケーキ食べいちゃうね、とどいちゃうね
You're gonna eat cake. You're gonna reach it.
だめですわ、そんなの
That won't do, not at all.
じゃあ次ね行きましょうか
Well then, let's go to the next one.
全然今さら、小走り、小走り
Seriously, now it's a trot, a trot.
小走り…
Trot...
やばい、5マス、6マスだって、消える
Oh no, 5 or 6 spaces, we'll disappear!
チン！
Ding!
これ最大が3なんだね、ごめんよ
The maximum is 3, huh. Sorry about that.
じゃ、3を出したい
Well, I want to roll a 3.
3を出したら、どこだ？ お嬢様？ お嬢様や
If I roll a 3, where is it? Ojou-sama? It's ojou-sama.
早くこっちに来るのですわ
Hurry up and come over here.
いや待ってこれ3なんて無理だよ、どんだけ地獄ないやん
Wait, a 3 is impossible! How much of a hell is this?
うわ、とどけー！
Woah, reach it!
次のターンまで「ミオしゃ小足」で移動
Move with "Mio-sha's tiny steps" until the next turn.
ってことでお嬢さ、小足小足、小足の小足
So ojou-sa... tiny steps, tiny steps!
よろしくお願いしますわー！
Please treat us kindly!
本当に！ 田舎の国からお嬢様です！ 田舎の国からっておかしい！ 田舎の国からって
Really! An ojou-sama from a rural country! From a rural country is weird! From a rural country...
じゃあね、次ね行きましょう
Well then, let's go to the next one.
ナイスー！
Nice!
お、お？
Oh? Oh?
お嬢様場所！ え、一緒！ お嬢様場所、え、小足のステップ？ 小さいステップ？
Ojou-sama tile! Eh, together! Ojou-sama tile, eh, tiny steps? Small steps?
小足ステップ、小足ステップ、小足ステップでね
Tiny step, tiny step, tiny step...
どっから来たお嬢様ですの？ わかんない、尻文字！ 何々々！？
Where did you come from, ojou-sama? I don't know, butt-writing! What what what?!
お嬢様いっぱいいる
There are so many ojou-samas.
えーと、宇宙… 宇宙…
Um, space... space...
でもさ、最悪な気分になるよね。心が傷ついてしまいますわー
But you know, it puts you in the worst mood. My heart gets hurt...
気分ですわー
Such a mood...
本当に！
Truly!
ではでは、次行きましょうはい
Well then, let's go to the next one, yes.
出た！
It rolled!
3ですね！
It's a 3!
1、2、3ですって。
1, 2, 3 it says.
素晴らしい、ジェスチャーゲーム！
Wonderful, Gesture Game!
ジェスチャーゲームですわ！
It's the Gesture Game!
お嬢様だよ、お嬢様！
It's an ojou-sama, ojou-sama!
初めてじゃん、うち。どうですわ？
It's our first time, us. How is it?
何をしてくださるのかしら？
What are you going to do for us?
あー、どうすればいいのこれ。おっ
Ah, what should I do here. Oh.
お？
Oh?
コアラ？ コアラだ！
Koala? It's a koala!
コアラ、コアラ！
Koala, koala!
すごい！ 素晴らしい！ さすが私たちのお嬢様！
Amazing! Wonderful! As expected of our ojou-sama!
お嬢様いっぱいいる。やったあ
There are so many ojou-samas. Yay!
じゃあこっちね
Then over here.
2マス進めよう。はい
Advance 2 spaces. Yes.
あ、ここでやった！
Ah, we did it here!
じゃあお嬢様のこちらの…
Well then, ojou-sama's here...
あ、行きなさい
Ah, go ahead.
相撲を解消したのに、解消したのに
Even though we resolved the sumo, even though we resolved it...
お嬢様どうぞ！
Ojou-sama, please!
お、なんばんだ？ 2！
Oh, what number? 2!
1、2。お、アイドルポーズ！
1, 2. Oh, Idol Pose!
お嬢様で、満場一致で2マスだって！
As an ojou-sama, unanimous agreement gets 2 spaces!
満場一致で2マスですの！？
Unanimous agreement gets 2 spaces?!
お、がんばれ！
Oh, do your best!
アイドルポーズは3つ。3つだよ
Idol poses are 3. Three of them!
え、これ持ったままですの？
Eh, holding this the whole time?
え、2ターンお嬢様ですから。そうだね、私たち
Eh, for 2 turns you're an ojou-sama. That's right, us.
はい！
Yes!
あ、じゃあどうぞ、アイドルポーズ
Ah, then go ahead, idol pose.
ふむ、1つめ？
Hm, the first one?
2つめ、2つめは？ さあ3つめは？
The second one, what about the second? Now, the third?
あー！
Ah!
どういたします皆さん、これ。どういたします？
What shall we do everyone, this. What shall we do?
ちょっと1つめ、ちょっと満場一致じゃありません！ もう一回させてくださいまし！
Wait, the first one, it wasn't unanimous! Please let us do it again!
ちょっとそれは
Wait, that's...
やりますわ！
We'll do it!
3つですの？ 新しい、新規3つでよろしいですか？
Three of them? Is new, three fresh ones okay?
新規3つ、でも…
Three fresh ones, but...
新規3つですの。1つ言うときどき私たちこの後あそこに増えたら…
Three fresh ones. Every time we say one, if we increase over there after this...
やりますわ！
We'll do it!
やりますわ私！
I will do it!
かっこいい！
Cool!
結構被りそうですけど大丈夫かな？
It looks like they might overlap quite a bit, but will it be okay?
記念すべき1回目どうぞどうぞじゃあ
Go right ahead for this memorable first time.
はい行きますわよ
Yes, I'm going!
1つ目
One...
2個目
Two...
3個目
Three...
4個目
Four...
なんですかこの！
What is this?!
待って2個目かぶってなかった？
Wait, didn't the second one overlap?
ちょっと待って
Wait, wait.
ちょっとなんかかぶってたかもね
Maybe it overlapped a bit.
両手も足も！両手も足も大サービスですわ、これ！
Both hands and feet! This is a huge service!
どうどうどう、どうします？
How, how, what should we do?
まあ1マスぐらいでいいんじゃないですか？進むのは。
Well, about one square should be fine, right?
確かに。
True.
そうですわ。
That's right.
1マス進む... 1マス進む？
Advance one square... advance one square?
じゃあお嬢様を踊らせていただきます。
Then, I will have the young lady dance.
ゲーミー風情が！
You gaming peasants!
うわ！うわ！
Whoa! Whoa!
最低最低だわ！
That's the absolute worst!
口臭えな！悪役令嬢だわ！
Your breath stinks! You're a villainess!
ちょっと口割れからやっぱ進みなさいよ。
Well, open your mouth wide and advance, after all.
口割れって何ですか？本当に！
What do you mean "split mouth"? Seriously!
歯っ汚い、歯っ汚い、歯っ汚い！
Dirty teeth, dirty teeth, dirty teeth!
汚いよ、言葉！
That's foul language!
進みます、1マスね。進んでください。お嬢様は？お嬢様は、はい。はい。
We advance one square. Please advance. The young lady? The young lady is, yes. Yes.
次... あ、じゃあじゃあ、どっち？
Next... Ah, then which one?
あ、じゃあジャンケンの飛ばしです。
Ah, then it's skipping via rock-paper-scissors.
あ、じゃあうちがね、次振ります。
Ah, then I'll roll next.
このままだと結構、独走状態になっちゃうからな。
If it stays like this, I'll end up in a runaway lead.
いやいやいや。
No, no, no.
よろしくないわね。
That's not good.
2！2！2！
2! 2! 2!
2、1、2、おっ！うおー！
2, 1, 2, Oh! Whoa!
健康になるお茶！健康になるお茶を飲む。
Health tea! Drink the health-boosting tea.
美味しそうに飲めなかったら2マス戻る。
If you can't drink it deliciously, go back 2 squares.
え、お茶を、お茶を、お茶を、お茶を。いつ？美味しそうに飲めなかったら2マス戻るだそうですよ。
Eh, tea, tea, tea, tea. When? If you can't drink it deliciously, you go back 2 squares, apparently.
え、結構美味しそうに飲まなきゃいけないですね。
Eh, you have to drink it like it's delicious.
これ、吹いちゃったら大丈夫ですか？掛けないでください、掛けないでください。
If I spit this out, will it be okay? Don't splash it, please.
スタッフさんが目を泳いでた。じゃあ...
The staff's eyes were darting around. Well...
お頑張りになって。お頑張りになって。
Do your best. Do your best.
大丈夫かな？
Will I be okay?
グイっと飲んだ。グイっと。
Drank it right down. Gulp.
飲めしちゃったもんね。
You managed to drink it.
これ、なんか...
This is, like...
何味ですか？これ。これは... なんか今まで食べたことのない味しますわ。
What flavor is this? This... tastes like something I've never eaten before.
ちょっと気になります。美味しかどうかどうかね。えっと...
I'm a bit curious. Whether it's delicious or not, um...
えっと...
Um...
もう数がおいしそうじゃないんだよ。目が泳いでますわ。
The numbers don't look appetizing at all. Her eyes are darting.
あの、風味はほとんどごぼうです。ごぼうですって！
Um, the flavor is mostly burdock root. Burdock root!
ごぼうなんだね。ごぼうのお茶なのかな？お父地の味がするということで。
It's burdock root. Is it burdock tea? It has a taste of... home.
そうですね、あの、森の土を水に溶いたみたいな味がします。
That's right, um, it tastes like forest soil dissolved in water.
お嬢様の味ですよね。めちゃめちゃマイナスなんですけど、大丈夫ですかね？
It's a young lady's taste. It's a huge minus, but is that okay?
そうですね。
That's right.
ね、美味しくなさそうなので、じゃあちょっと2マス戻っていただき...
Well, it doesn't look delicious, so please go back 2 squares...
え！そんなことないですもん！
Eh! It's not like that!
美味しい。ね。はい残念。
Delicious. Right? Well, too bad.
ちょっとMioのリアクション撮っちゃったわ。そう、シビアですわね。
We caught Mio's reaction. Yeah, it's severe.
そして私、おサイフを折込に...
And me, folding my wallet...
来なさい、ここに！
Come here, to this spot!
優雅ですわ。
How elegant.
2マスですのよ。
It's 2 squares.
どういうこと？アイドルポーズ？
What do you mean? Idol pose?
アイドルポーズを3つ！満場一致で2マス進む！
Do 3 idol poses! Advance 2 squares with unanimous agreement!
はい、じゃあ1個目。
Okay, then the first one.
1個目。
First one.
ああー！
Ahhh!
1個目！
First one!
2個目！
Second one!
お顔が...お顔が全額れですわね。
Your face... your face is completely exposed.
3個目は？
What about the 3rd one?
3個目？
3rd one?
ああー！4個目は？4個目？
Ahhh! What about the 4th one? 4th one?
4個目は...あ、4個目！
The 4th one is... Ah, the 4th one!
ではこちらどうですか皆さん？キングタイムでね。
So, how is this, everyone? It's king time.
どうですか？
How is it?
私、6ついたしましたよ。
I did six of them, you know.
自分です、進むぞって。
You said you'd advance yourself.
自分でおっしゃってたじゃない。
You said it yourself, didn't you?
ワンチャンスください、おっしゃって。
Please give me one chance, you said.
私も結構よかったですけどね。ちょっとでも...
Mine was pretty good, though. Even a bit...
曲がりましたよね。ちょっと。
It bent, didn't it? A bit.
センスで顔コレクターの1マスかな？
Is it one square for face collector with sense?
1マスね、1マスね。
One square, one square.
まあまわ、お嬢様お嬢様だから1マスは喜んで受けますけどね。
Well, you're a young lady, so I'll gladly accept 1 square.
なんですか、あなた！あなた！
What is it, you! You!
あなたみたいに僕にも、ありがたく進まさせていただきます。ねえ、お嬢様。
Like you, I'll gladly advance as well. Right, young lady.
そうですわよ、お嬢様。
That's right, young lady.
じゃあちょっと振りますわよ。
Then I'll roll a bit.
ちょっと振りますわよ。
I'll roll a bit.
次こそは優雅に...
Next time, gracefully...
お、初めて？
Oh, for the first time?
お、初めてです。
Oh, it's my first time.
出た！
It's here!
全員とじゃんけん！
Janken with everyone!
全勝！全勝！はあー！
Win them all! Win them all! Haah!
負けたら、1マス戻るぞ。
If I lose, I go back one space.
よーし、最初はグー、じゃんけん、ほい！
Alright, rock, paper, scissors, go!
あいこでしょ！
Aiko desho!
あー！勝った！
Ah! I won!
当然ですわ。
Naturally.
最初はグー、じゃんけん、ほい！
Rock, paper, scissors, go!
あいこでしょ、あいこでしょ、あいこでしょ、あいこでしょ、あいこでしょ！
Aiko desho, aiko desho, aiko desho...
あー！負けた！1マス戻るぞ！
Ah! I lost! Going back one space!
最初はグー、じゃんけん、ほい！
Rock, paper, scissors, go!
あいこでしょ！
Aiko desho!
あ、負けた、1マス戻る！
Ah, I lost, going back one space!
最初はグー、じゃんけん、ほい、あいこでしょ、あいこでしょ！
Rock, paper, scissors, go, aiko desho, aiko desho!
えい！負けました！1マス戻るです！
Hey! I lost! Going back one space!
さようなら。
Goodbye.
全然進みません。
I'm not making any progress at all.
またお遊びにいらして。
Come play with us again.
次は、次は長いのかな？
Next, is the next one long?
みたんと長いのと？
Mitan and a long one?
え？いつもそうだっけ？長いのよ。
Eh? Is it always like this? It's long.
1、2、3、おっ！何これ？
1, 2, 3, Oh! What's this?
おおかみみお！
Ookami Mio!
大神ミオに関するクイズを出題、答えると……
A quiz about Ookami Mio! If you answer...
ええと、答えが正解だった場合はもうゴールに直進！
Um, if the answer is correct, straight to the goal!
そして、もし外れた場合は再会と場所がチェンジされるよ！
And if you get it wrong, you swap places with last place!
私、めちゃめちゃいい！
I'm doing great!
全然ちがうと。
Not at all.
当たったよ、当たったよ。
You got it right.
やるわけねえでしょ！
No way!
というわけで、じゃあ、うちからの大神ミオ、クイズー！イエーイ！
So, here is the Ookami Mio quiz from me! Yay!
大神ミオが唯一得意としている球技は何でしょうか？
What is the only ball sport Ookami Mio is good at?
唯一得意としてる球技。
The only ball sport she's good at.
難しいわね。
That's difficult.
選択肢を、あ、選択肢3つ、はい。
Options, ah, 3 options, yes.
はい。おいおい。
Yes. Hey now.
1、バスケットボール。
1, Basketball.
2、ソフトボール。
2, Softball.
3、ドッジボール！どっちボール！
3, Dodgeball! Which ball?!
正解は？
The correct answer is?
なんの？どっちボール？
Which? Dodgeball?
え？正解！やったー！
Eh? Correct! Yay!
え、ドッジボール得意だったの？
Eh, you were good at dodgeball?
うん。うちはドッジボールで外野でバシバシ当てすぎたら、女の子が泣いちゃって、男の子に混じってドッジボールやれって言われました。
Yeah. If I hit too hard from the outfield in dodgeball, the girls would cry, and I was told to play dodgeball mixed with the boys.
悲しい話。
A sad story.
悲しいクラスにいるタイプ。
The type in a sad class.
こい、外野からいっぱい狙ってくるタイプ怖いよ。
Coming from the outfield and targeting you a lot is scary.
強い外野が、外野がやばいです。
Strong outfielders, the outfield is dangerous.
というわけでも正解だった！
So she got it right too!
白上フブキがゴールに到達ということで！
Shirakami Fubuki has reached the goal!
ゴールなんですね？
It's the goal?
すごいですね。
That's amazing.
にゃお、ゴール！
Nyao, goal!
おめでとうございます！けっきょよ、やったー！
Congratulations! Kekkyoyo, yay!
フブさまのも、フブさまよ！
Fubu-sama's too, Fubu-sama!
あの、はい、あの、おめでとうございます、おめでとうございます。
Um, yes, um, congratulations, congratulations.
おめでとうございます。
Congratulations.
え、食べるのかな？食べてもらっていいですよ。
Eh, will you eat it? You can eat it.
本当ですか？またじゃあ、いただいてみましょう。
Really? Then let's try having some.
あ、そうね。大きいケーキ来たこと。フブちゃんぽい、美味しそうだな。
Ah, right. A big cake arrived. It looks like Fubu-chan, looks delicious.
何のケーキなの？それは誕生日ケーキでいい、いいのよね？誕生日ケーキなんだよね、毎回好きケーキだよ。
What kind of cake is it? It's a birthday cake, right? It's a birthday cake every time.
誕生日ケーキ食べてる気がする。あ、そうだね。
Feels like I'm eating a birthday cake. Ah, that's right.
え？フブちゃん誕生日おめでとう！
Eh? Happy birthday, Fubu-chan!
お誕生日おめでとう！おめでとう！
Happy birthday! Congratulations!
お嬢様らしいわよ。お嬢様っぽい。
Like an ojou-sama. Ojou-sama-like.
お嬢様方も食べられます。
Ojou-samas can eat too.
やろうぜ！やろうぜ！ちょっとこの選手置いといてか。
Let's do it! Let's do it! Put this player aside.
ちょっとお嬢様人もどうぞ、どうぞ、よければ。
Ojou-sama people too, please, if you'd like.
お誕生日おめでとうございます、みたいな。
Happy birthday to you, or something.
えい！
Hey!
お、みお先輩、お誕生日おめでとうございます。
Oh, Mio-senpai, happy birthday.
すごいヤバイ。お嬢様を持たされちゃって。
That's crazy. Being made to hold ojou-sama.
木のんだや。
Kinonda ya.
めちゃめちゃ顔面で塗るたく、取り上げ。
Smearing it all over my face, taking it away.
それにシグナルにいやなやつ。
And a nasty signal to it.
つけ抜けちゃった。
Got carried away.
みおしゃ、お誕生日
Mio-sha, happy birthday
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
おめで、おめで
Congra-, congra-
シンプル嫌なやつ。
Simply a nasty guy.
2人目。
Second person.
だも。さすがに度はね。
Damo. As expected of Towa.
さすがにね。さすがにね。
As expected. As expected.
まずフォークがないから。
First of all, there's no fork.
さすがにね。
As expected.
どうやって食べるのかな？
How are we supposed to eat it?
ケーキを食べる資格が
The qualification to eat cake
みおちゃん！
Mio-chan!
お誕生日…おめでとう！
Happy birthday!
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
ミオしゃ、来年もね、こうやってみんなでお祝いしようね！
Mio-sha, let's celebrate together like this again next year!
そうだね！
That's right!
来年もごちになります！
Looking forward to next year's feast too!
お疲れ様です！
Good work!
いや、来年こそうちもケーキ食べたいよ！
No, next year I want to eat cake too!
じゃあ募集ということで、
Then recruitment starts!
あとはじゃあ、これ片付けておきますのでね。
I'll clean this up in the meantime.
ミオしゃおめでとう！
Mio-sha, congratulations!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ありがとう、ケーキ！
Thank you, cake!
え、めっちゃ美味しそう！
Eh, it looks so delicious!
このクリームついてる、つーか、ぎょっか…
This cream attached, wait, Gyokka...
ペロペロさせるってこと？屈辱的！
Making me lick it? How humiliating!
ペロペロ…
Lick lick...
というわけで以上、誕生日夏の地獄すごろくでした！
And with that, that was the Birthday Summer Hell Sugoroku!
おめでとー！
Congratulations!
歌をお楽しみください！
Please enjoy the song!
カレンダーより早く
Earlier than the calendar,
早く
early
シャツの袖口まくって
rolling up my shirt sleeves.
太陽が近づく気配
Feels like the sun is getting closer.
僕の腕から衣替え
Changing clothes from my arms.
青い海 波打ち際で
At the edge of the blue sea and waves,
君と会いたい 裸足の水しぶき
I want to meet you, barefoot splashing water.
ポニーテール揺らしながら
Your ponytail swinging
風の中
in the wind.
君が走る 僕が走る
You run, I run
砂の上
on the sand.
ポニーテール揺らしながら 振り向いた
Your ponytail swinging as you turned back.
君の笑顔 僕の夏が始まる
Your smile, my summer begins.
教室に日が射して
The sun shines into the classroom,
夢の気温が上がった
the temperature of my dreams has risen.
斜め前の君見ていると
When I look at you sitting diagonally in front,
胸が苦しくなってくる
my chest starts to ache.
好きなんて言えやしないよ
I can never say that I like you.
後ろ姿に気持ちをつぶやく
Murmuring my feelings to your back.
ポニーテール切なくなる 夢の中
Your ponytail makes me feel sad, inside a dream.
君のすべて 僕のすべて一人占め
Wanting all of you, all of me, all to myself.
ポニーテール切なくなる 片想い
Your ponytail makes me feel sad, unrequited love.
瞳と瞳合えば 今はただの友達
When our eyes meet, we're just friends right now.
束ねた長い髪 水玉のシュシュ
Tied long hair, a polka-dot scrunchie.
恋の尻尾は 捕まえられない
The tail of love cannot be caught.
触れたら消えてく 幻
If I touch it, it disappears like an illusion.
ポニーテールほどかないで 変わらずに
Don't untie your ponytail, stay unchanged.
君は君で 僕は僕で 走るだけ
You are you, I am me, just running.
ポニーテール ほどかないで
Don't untie your ponytail.
いつまでも
Forever and ever,
はしゃいでいる
you're playing around,
君は少女のままで
staying just like a young girl.
LaLaLa...
La la la...
夏が何度も巡り来ても
No matter how many summers come round,
忘れないでいたい
I want to never forget them,
ずっと
always...
少し寂しいと思ったんだ
I thought I felt a little lonely,
浴衣の袖を揺らす
swishing the sleeves of my yukata.
「風が涼しいね」なんて言った
"The breeze is cool, isn't it?" you said,
君の表情見つけたいかな
hoping to catch a glimpse of your expression.
オレンジが縁取ったシルエット
A silhouette edged in orange light,
蝉の歌う声や 波の騒めき
the cicadas singing, the murmuring waves.
遠くなっていったって
Even if they grow distant,
きっと思い出せる
I'm sure we can remember them.
祭りの夜の空を見ると
When I look at the festival's night sky,
まるで思い出の数だけ
it's just like the number of memories,
色が光っているみたいだね
with each color shining brightly.
一つ一つ綺麗に
One by one, beautifully,
咲いて 咲いて いくよ
they bloom and bloom on.
新しい浴衣着替えて
Changing into a new yukata,
「どうかな？」って見せ合ったり
"How does it look?" we showed each other.
気温のせいにしちゃって
Blaming it on the temperature,
熱い気持ちで未来を語ったり
we talked about the future with passion.
どんなことでも冒険みたいになる
Everything feels like an adventure,
期待値が上がってしまうシーズン
in this season where expectations run high.
当たり前の日も 特別ってこと
Even ordinary days are special,
この瞬間 この一瞬だって 思わせる
making us feel that this very moment is precious.
賑わう人で混み合うほど
The more crowded the bustling crowd gets,
何だか楽しい気分だね
the more joyful the mood somehow feels.
動画の窓のような屋台
Stalls like windows in a moving video,
一つ一つ覗いて
peeking into each and every one.
一緒に 一緒に 歩こう
Let's walk together, side by side.
振り返っても
Even if I look back,
ほんのちょっとも トリミング出来ないようなシーンばっかり
every single scene is untrimmable, not even a bit.
過ぎ去ってしまう前にもう一度だけ みんなといたい
Before it slips away, I want to be with everyone just once more.
想い出たちを彩るように 夜空に咲いた花火が
Like fireworks blooming in the night sky to color our memories,
色鮮やかに輝いてた
they shone so vividly.
ずっと…一緒にいたいよ
I want to stay together... forever.
"I want to stay together... forever."
来年もまたこんな風に 笑い合いたいって思うから
Hoping that next year we can laugh together
線香花火に願うんだ
Just like a sparkler, I make a wish
「ずっと ずっと 続いて」
"May it go on and on, forever,"
きっと きっと 叶う
I'm sure, I'm sure it will come true.
はい！というわけで、えー
Right! So, um...
スパークルズでした。
That was Sparkle!
いや、いい曲だよね。
Yeah, it's such a good song, right?
あー、でもなんかみんな居なくなっちゃって
Ah, but since everyone has gone home,
ちょっと寂しいけど
I'm a bit lonely.
ここで、大神ミオ 誕生日記念グッズの紹介をさせてもらいます！
Now, I'd like to introduce Ookami Mio's...
まずはこちら！
Birthday commemoration merchandise!
1個目のグッズは、B2のタペストリーです！
First up is the B2 Tapestry!
こちらね、あの泉先生のね、描き下ろしとなっておりますので、
This features illustration by Izumi-sensei.
泉パパのね、はい、すごいかわいい、夏らしくて、水着のタペストリーなんですけど、うちと一緒にちょっと海に行った気分になれるかなと思って、こんな感じのイラスト描いていただきました！パパありがとう！
It's super cute and gives off a nice summer vibe! Thank you, Papa!
そして、お次のグッズがこちら！もこもこみおしゃアクリルタンブラー！
And the next item is... the Mokomoko Miosha Acrylic Tumbler!
こちらなんですけど、なんと、えーうちがもこもこのみおしゃを描き下ろしました！いえーい！
Look at that—I drew all these little Mokomoko Mioshas myself! Yay!
なんか結構大きいサイズのタンブラーだから、なんかうちもね、こういうタンブラーあるといいなと思って作ってみたんです！こうぐびぐびとね、たくさん飲めるようなカップにしてあるので、ぜひぜひ配信のおともにいかがでしょうか。
It's a pretty large tumbler, so I hope you'll use it while hanging out in my streams!
そして、お次のグッズがこちら！ミオとおそろいラバー前髪クリップ！
And the next item is... the Mio and Matching Rubber Bangs Clip!
これですね、これこれこれこれ。はい。こちらのね、あの前髪のクリップの、えーと、ま、あのクリップ上でくっつくようにはなってるんですけれど、ま、前髪をとめてもいいですし、ま、ちょっとね、あの前髪にとめるのはちょっと恥ずかしいかもっていう人は、え、カバンとかにね、くっつけてもいいんじゃないかなって思って作ってみました！2コセットなので、ぜひぜひ幅広く使ってみてください！
This is a set of two, so please use them however you like!
はい、というわけで、え、今回ですねこの3つのグッズ、全てのフルセットをご購入いただいた方に、え、うちの、え、複製サイン入りの、え、チェキ風ブロマイドカードを！
So, if you purchase the full set of these three items,
特典ボイス、お祝いありがとうお礼ボイスということで、ま、ボイスというか、ま、うちの今回フルセット買ってくれてありがとうという気持ちの、お礼の、え、言葉を込めた、え、ボイスを特典としてお付けいたしますので、よかったら聞いてみてください！
And special voice clips as a bonus!
はい。うーん。
So...
まあね、ここまですごろくやったりとか、みんなでわーって歌ったりとか、すごい楽しい思い出になったな、今年も。
We've shared so many stories and sang together this year.
ちょっとケーキは食べられなかったけど、え、みんなもたくさんお祝いしてくれてありがとう！
Thank you all so much for celebrating with me!
で、ここでね、あの最後に一曲、うちがソロで歌わせてもらうんだけれども、うちが歌った後にも、なんと、うーん、すごい重大発表がありますので、ぜひぜひ最後まで見ていってくれると嬉しいです！よろしくお願いします！みんな今日お祝いありがとね！
And now, I have one final, super important announcement!
じゃあ、最後に歌わせていただきます。
Let's hear it one last time.
君と夏の終わり
The end of summer with you,
将来の夢 大きな希望 忘れない
future dreams and big hopes I won't forget.
10年後の8月 また出逢えるのを信じて
Believing we'll meet again in August, ten years from now,
最高の思い出を…
for the best memories...
出会いはふとした瞬間
Our meeting was a fleeting moment,
帰り道の交差点で
at the intersection on the way home,
声をかけてくれたね「一緒に帰ろう」
you called out to me, "Let's go home together."
僕は照れくさそうに
I acted all embarrassed,
カバンで顔を隠しながら
hiding my face behind my bag,
本当はとても とても 嬉しかったよ
though the truth is, I was so, so happy.
ああ 花火が夜空
Ah, fireworks in the night sky
きれいに咲いて ちょっとセツナク
bloom so beautifully, making me a bit sad.
ああ 風が時間とともに流れる
Ah, the wind flows away with time.
嬉しくって 楽しくって 冒険もいろいろしたね
So happy, so fun, we had all sorts of adventures
二人の秘密の基地の中
inside our secret hideout.
君と夏の終わり
The end of summer with you,
将来の夢 大きな希望 忘れない
future dreams and big hopes I won't forget.
10年後の8月 また出逢えるのを信じて
Believing we'll meet again in August, ten years from now,
君が最後まで 心から
I knew you were shouting
「ありがとう」叫んでいたこと 知っていたよ
"Thank you" from your heart until the very end.
涙をこらえて 笑顔でさようなら せつないよね
Holding back tears, smiling to say goodbye is so sad.
最高の思い出を…
For the best memories...
ああ 夏休みもあと少しで終わっちゃうから
Ah, summer break will be over soon,
ああ 太陽と月 仲良くして
ah, sun and moon, get along well.
悲しくって 寂しくって 喧嘩もいろいろしたね
So sad, so lonely, we had various fights too
二人の秘密の基地の中
inside our secret hideout.
君が最後まで
I knew you shouted
心から「ありがとう」叫んでいたこと 知っていたよ
"Thank you" from your heart until the very end.
涙をこらえて 笑顔でさようなら せつないよね
Holding back tears, smiling to say goodbye is so sad.
最高の思い出を…
For the best memories...
突然の 転校で
With a sudden transfer,
どうしようもなく
feeling so helpless,
手紙書くよ 電話もするよ
I'll write letters, I'll call you too,
忘れないでね 僕のことを
so don't forget about me.
いつでも 二人の秘密の基地の中
Forever inside our secret hideout.
君と夏の終わり ずっと話して 夕日を見てから星を眺め
The end of summer with you, talking all day, watching the sunset and stars.
君の頬を流れた 涙は ずっと忘れない
I'll never forget the tears streaming down your cheek.
君が最後まで 大きく手を振ってくれたこと きっと忘れない
I'll never forget you waving goodbye with all your might.
だからこうして 夢の中で ずっと永遠に
So like this, in my dreams, forever and ever.
君と夏の終わり
The end of summer with you,
将来の夢 大きな希望 忘れない
future dreams and big hopes I won't forget.
10年後の8月 また出逢えるのを信じて
Believing we'll meet again in August, ten years from now,
君が最後まで 心から「ありがとう」叫んでいたこと 知っていたよ
I knew you shouted "Thank you" from your heart until the very end.
涙をこらえて 笑顔でさようなら せつないよね
Holding back tears, smiling to say goodbye is so sad.
最高の思い出を…
For the best memories...
さあ行こう 待ち焦がれた
Let's go, toward the yearning
未来へと 突き進み響く
future, pressing forward and echoing.
言葉にできず 見つめ合うだけ
Unable to speak, just gazing at each other.
届くよね そう今日も 優しいかたちのまま
It reaches you, right? Even today, in its gentle form.
真夜中 流れてく ビルをなぞって
Flowing through the midnight, tracing the buildings,
消える どこへゆくの
fading away. Where are you going?
変わっていくこと 気づいて
Realizing things are changing,
立ち止まった
I came to a stop.
曖昧で確かなもの 終わりあることだから
Vague yet certain things, because they have an end.
私は ここにある
I am right here.
君といる時間の中で息をする
Breathing within the time I spend with you.
変わないでと 終わらないでと
"Don't change," "Don't end," —
今日も 夜明けを噛む
today too, I bite into the dawn.
輝いていたい こんな世界で
I want to shine in a world like this,
憂う 私をどうか
so please, for grieving me—
寝かさないで
don't let me sleep.
君の隣で 溶けて消えるまで
Until I melt and fade by your side,
生きて
live.
うっちー、うちだよ！大神ミオです。
Utchii, it's me! I'm Ookami Mio.
みんな、今日はたくさん楽しんでくれたかな？
Everyone, did you have lots of fun today?
なんと、ファーストアルバムの発売が決定しました！
And guess what? My 1st album release has been decided!
予約は今日から始まるので、詳しくはTwitterやYouTubeのコミュニティでお知らせします。
Reservations start today, so check Twitter and YouTube community posts for details.
また、この後新曲のアニメーションMVが公開されます。
Also, a new animated music video will premiere right after this.
この枠にいると自動的に移動するので、一緒に聞いてくれたら嬉しいな。
You'll be automatically moved while in this room, so I hope you'll listen along with me.
それじゃあ、今日は本当に お祝いしてくれてありがとう！
Well then, thank you so much for celebrating with me today!
楽しくて幸せな最高の誕生日になったよ。
It became the happiest, most wonderful birthday ever.
またいつもの配信で会おうね！おつみょーん、このまま移動なー！
Let's meet again on our usual streams! Otsumyoon, time to move on!